<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Ta Bao Lan]]></title>
  <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-23T15:20:11+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ta Bao Lan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newbie Part 4 : Configuration Eclipse With Selenium Driver and Create Fisrt Test]]></title>
    <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/23/newbie-part-4-configuration-eclipse-with-selenium-driver-and-create-fisrt-test/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-23T15:13:27+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/23/newbie-part-4-configuration-eclipse-with-selenium-driver-and-create-fisrt-test</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Creat a simple test case selenium in Eclipse</h2>

<p>To configure Eclipse with Selenium webdriver, we need to launch the Eclipse IDE, create a Workspace, create a Project, create a Package, create a Class and add External libraries to the project.</p>

<p>&mdash; Để cài Selenium vào Eclipse , chúng ta phải mở Eclipse IDE , tạo 1 workspace , tạo 1 project , tạo 1 package , và một Class.Tất nhiên chúng ta cũng phải thêm những file jar cần thiết vào cái project đấy.</p>

<h3>1) Select WorkSpace on Eclipse start up.</h3>

<p>&mdash; Chọn workspace khi Eclipse khởi động.</p>

<p>a) Double click on ‘eclipse.exe’ to start eclipse. First time when you start eclipse, it will ask you to select your workspace where your work will be stored as shown in below image.</p>

<p>&mdash; Ấn chuột 2 lần vào file &lsquo;eclipse.exe&rsquo; để mở eclipse.Lần đầu tiên bạn mở eclipse , nó sẽ hỏi bạn chọn workspace để lưu trữ project của bạn.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Start-Eclipse-1.png"></p>

<p>b) Create a “working directory” for all of your projects. Think of it like “My Documents” in the Windows operating system. It’s a folder which contains a lot of your documents, but there’s nothing to prevent you from creating another folder called “My Other Documents” (for instance) to house other documents.</p>

<p>Typically you only need one workspace, and you can think of it as your “My Documents” for Java code. If you wanted to, you could have more than one, but chances are you won’t have a use for more. I like to choose my own workplace location and will place all my ToolsQA tutorial projects under it.</p>

<p>You can change it later on from ‘Switch Workspace‘ under ‘File‘ menu of eclipse. After selecting workspace folder, Eclipse will be open.</p>

<p>&mdash; Workspace là nơi để lưu trữ project của bạn , bạn hoàn toàn có thể tạo nhiều workspace để lưu trữ khác nhau tùy vào bạn.Bạn có thể chuyển đổi workspace bằng cách ấn vào menu File trên đầu màn hình và chọn &lsquo;Switch Workspace&rsquo;.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Start-Eclipse-21.png"></p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Start-Eclipse-3.png"></p>

<p>c) You may see the window like this, this is the Welcome window for Eclipse. You may close this window.</p>

<p>&mdash; Bạn có thể thấy 1 màn hình như hình dưới đây,đấy là màn hình chào mừng của Eclipse.Bạn hoàn toàn có thể đóng màn hình đó lại cũng không sao.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Start-Eclipse-4.png"></p>

<h3>2) Create a new Project</h3>

<p>&mdash; Tạo mới 1 Project</p>

<p>Projects: A collection of related code. Generally speaking, each project encompasses one independent program. Each programming assignment you do will typically require its own project.</p>

<p>Once you’ve established your workspace, you’ll want to create a project and begin writing code. In Eclipse, projects are the next-smallest functional unit after workspaces, but where you might have only one workspace, you will usually have several projects inside one workspace.</p>

<p>&mdash; Project là nơi chúng ta lưu code.Ở Eclipse thì Project là đối tượng nhỏ hơn Workspace.</p>

<p>a) Create new Java Project from File > New > Project .</p>

<p>&mdash; Tạo mới 1 project Java từ menu File > New > Project.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Setup-Project-1.png"></p>

<p>b) Select Java Project and click Next.</p>

<p>&mdash; Chọn vào mục Java Project và ấn vào nút có chữ &ldquo;Next&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Setup-Project-2.png"></p>

<p>c) Give your Project name ‘OnlineStore‘ as shown in below given figures. Click on Finish button.</p>

<p>&mdash; Đặt tên cho Project của bạn là &ldquo;OnlineStore&rdquo; như hình phía dưới và ấn nút có chữ &ldquo;Finish&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Setup-Project-3.png"></p>

<p>d) You may or may not see this message but if in case you get any, check Remember my decision and  click on Yes.</p>

<p>&mdash; Bạn có thể thấy hoặc không thấy cái dòng chữ phía dưới nhưng nếu thấy thì bạn cứ ấn vào cái checkbox &ldquo;Remember my decision&rdquo; và ấn nút có chữ &ldquo;Yes&rdquo;.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Setup-Project-4.png"></p>

<h3>3) Create a new Package</h3>

<p>&mdash; Tạo mới 1 Package</p>

<p>a) Right click on Project name ‘OnlineStore‘ and select New > Package.</p>

<p>&mdash; Ấn chuột phải vào Project &ldquo;OnlineStore&rdquo; và ấn vào menu New > Package.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Creating-Package-1.png"></p>

<p>b) Give your Package name ‘automationFramework‘ and click on Finish button.</p>

<p>&mdash; Đặt tên cho Package là &lsquo;automationFramework&rsquo; và ấn vào nút &lsquo;Finish&rsquo;.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Creating-Package-2.png"></p>

<h3>4) Create a new Class</h3>

<p>&mdash; Tạo mới 1 Class.</p>

<p>Now that you have a project set up, you’re going to want start writing some new classes.</p>

<p>&mdash; Sau khi hoàn thành việc tạo project và package , bây giờ bạn sẽ tạo 1 class và bắt đầu viết code.</p>

<p>a) Right click on Package ‘automationFramework‘ and select New > Class.</p>

<p>&mdash; Click chuột phải vào Package có tên là  &lsquo;automationFramework&rsquo; và chọn New > Class.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Creating-Class-1.png"></p>

<p>b)  Give your Class name ‘FirstTestCase‘, check the option ‘public static void main‘ and click on Finish button. This will bring up totally a sweet class creation window.</p>

<p>Note: In case of not creating class for Main test case, please do not click ‘public static void main’. We need to select it only in case of writing test cases which we are going to execute and from where we call other classes. For functional classes, POM classes or any other classes we dont need this to be checked.</p>

<p>&mdash; Đặt tên cho Class của bạn là &lsquo;FirstTestCase&rsquo; và chọn thêm 1 cái lựa chọn là &lsquo;public static void main&rsquo; và cuối cùng là ấn vào nút &lsquo;Finish&rsquo;. Nó sẽ tạo ra 1 class mà có hầu hết các function chính.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Creating-Class-2.png"></p>

<p>c) Now your Eclipse window will looks like bellow.</p>

<p>&mdash; Bây giờ màn hình Eclipse của bạn sẽ giống như hình dưới đây.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Creating-Class-3.png"></p>

<h3>5) Add External Jars to Java build path</h3>

<p>Now you need to add selenium webdriver’s jar files in to Java build path.</p>

<p>&mdash; Bây giờ bạn phải cài selenium webdriver vào trong Java Build Path.</p>

<p>a) Right click on Project ‘OnlineStore‘ > Select Properties > Java build path. Then navigate to Libraries tab and click Add External JARs.</p>

<p>&mdash; Ấn chuột phải vào Project &lsquo;OnlineStore&rsquo; > Select Properties > Java build path . Chuyển đến Libraries và ấn vào Add External Jars.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Selenium-Jar-1.png"></p>

<p>b) Add Selenium Java jar, you may add the source file too.</p>

<p>&mdash; Chọn file Selenium Java jar , bạn cũng có thể chọn các file source khác.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Selenium-Jar-2.png"></p>

<p>c) Add all the jars from the libs folder as well.</p>

<p>&mdash; Chọn tất cả cái file jars trong folder libs nữa nhé.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Selenium-Jar-3.png"></p>

<p>d) Click OK.</p>

<p>&mdash; Ấn nút Ok.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Selenium-Jar-4.png"></p>

<p>That’s all about configuration of WebDriver with eclipse. Now you are ready to write your test script in eclipse and run it in WebDriver.</p>

<p>&mdash; Đây là tất cả những bước cài đặt Webdriver vào trong Eclipse. Giờ bạn đã sẵn sàng để viết những dòng code của  bạn trong Epclise và chạy nó trên nền WebDriver của Selenium.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Selenium-Jar-5.png"></p>

<h3>6) Write your First Test Case</h3>

<p>a) Copy &amp; paste the below code to your First Test Case class and give it a run.</p>

<p>&mdash; Copy và paste đoạn code ở dưới vào file class FirstTestCase mà bạn vừa tạo.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
<span class='line-number'>35</span>
<span class='line-number'>36</span>
<span class='line-number'>37</span>
<span class='line-number'>38</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>package automationFramework;
</span><span class='line'>import java.util.concurrent.TimeUnit;
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>import org.openqa.selenium.*;
</span><span class='line'>import org.openqa.selenium.firefox.FirefoxDriver;
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>public class FirstTestCase {
</span><span class='line'>    private static WebDriver driver = null;
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>    public static void main(String[] args) {
</span><span class='line'>        // Create a new instance of the Firefox driver
</span><span class='line'>        driver = new FirefoxDriver();
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>        //Put a Implicit wait, this means that any search for elements on the page could take the time the implicit wait is set for before throwing exception
</span><span class='line'>        driver.manage().timeouts().implicitlyWait(10, TimeUnit.SECONDS);
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>        //Launch the facebook
</span><span class='line'>        driver.get("https://www.facebook.com/");
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>        
</span><span class='line'>        // Find the element that's ID attribute is 'email' (Username)
</span><span class='line'>        // Enter email on the element found by above desc.
</span><span class='line'>      driver.findElement(By.id("email")).sendKeys('enter your username login to facebook')
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>        // Find the element that's ID attribute is 'pass' (Password)
</span><span class='line'>        // Enter Password on the element found by the above desc.
</span><span class='line'>         driver.findElement(By.id("pass")).sendKeys("enter your password login to facebook"); 
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>        // Now submit the form. WebDriver will find the form for us from the element 
</span><span class='line'>        driver.findElement(By.Xpath("//form[@id='login_form']/table/tbody/tr[2]/td[3]/label/input")).click();
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>        // Print a Log In message to the screen
</span><span class='line'>        System.out.println(" Login Successfully, now it is the time to Log Off buddy.");
</span><span class='line'> 
</span><span class='line'>        // Close the driver
</span><span class='line'>        driver.quit();
</span><span class='line'>            }
</span><span class='line'>    }</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>2) Now, to start the test just select Run > Run As > Java Application Or Right Click on Eclipse code and Click Run As  > Java Application</p>

<p>&mdash; Bạn hãy chạy dòng code trên bằng cách chuột phải vào class &lsquo;FisrtTestCase&rsquo; chọn Run > Run As > Java Application.</p>

<p>3) After a few Seconds a Mozilla browser will open  and you will see that with the help of your script, Selenium will Launch the Online Store, perform Sign in, display the Message, perform Log out and then Close the browser.</p>

<p>Once the execution is finished, you will see the message in Console section of the Eclipse IDE.</p>

<p>&mdash; Sau mấy giây , trình duyệt FireFox (bạn nhớ phải cài trình duyệt này từ trước nhé) sẽ mở lên bạn sẽ thấy nó chạy dựa theo dòng code mà bạn đã viết trước đó.Sau khi hoàn thành nó sẽ đóng trình duyệt và màn hình Console của Eclipse IDE sẽ mở ra.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newbie Part 3 : Download Webdriver Java Client]]></title>
    <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-3-download-webdriver-java-client/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T16:49:41+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-3-download-webdriver-java-client</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Download WebDriver Java client (Tải về Webdriver Java client)</h2>

<p>Selenium webdriver supports many languages and each language has its own client driver. Here we are configuring selenium 2 with Java so we need ‘webdriver Java client driver’.</p>

<p>&mdash; Selenium hỗ trợ nhiều ngôn ngữ và mỗi một ngôn ngữ sẽ có 1 driver riêng.Ở đây chúng ta sẽ thiết lật Selenium 2 với Java nên chúng ta cần driver dành cho Java.</p>

<p>1) <a href="http://docs.seleniumhq.org/download/">Click here</a> to go on WebDriver Java client driver download page for webdriver download file. On that page click on ‘Download‘ link of Java client driver as shown in the below image.</p>

<p>&mdash; Nhấp chuột vào <a href="http://docs.seleniumhq.org/download/">đây</a> để đi tới website cho phép tải về driver của Selenium.Ở trang đó bạn nhấp chuột vào chữ &ldquo;Download&rdquo; của driver dành cho Java như hình phía dưới.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-1.png"></p>

<p>2) Save the zip file to your disk.</p>

<p>&mdash; Lưu file zip vào ổ đĩa máy tính.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-2.png"></p>

<p>3) Once you have downloaded the archive you will need to Extract the zip file, which will create the unzipped Selenium Java folder.</p>

<p>&mdash; Tải về thành công bạn phải giải nén file đã tải về để tạo ra folder Selenium Java</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-3.png"></p>

<p>4) You may want to Extract the archive to the folder where you are maintaing the test ware for your project. I like to extract it at the same location and then move it as per my needs.</p>

<p>&mdash; Chọn ổ đĩa bạn muốn giải nén.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-4.png"></p>

<p>5) Once the extraction process is complete, Open the Selenium folder.</p>

<p>&mdash; Khi việc giải nén hoàn tất , đi đến ổ đĩa mà lưu giữ folder Selenium</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-5.png"></p>

<p>6) There will be ‘libs’ folder, 2 jar files and change log in unzipped folder as shown in bellow figure. We will use all these files for configuring webdriver in eclipse.</p>

<p>&mdash; Bạn sẽ phải dùng tất cả các file và folder bên trong folder Selenium để thiết lập webdriver với cả eclipse.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-6.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newbie Part 2 : Download and Start Eclipse]]></title>
    <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-2-download-and-start-eclipse/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T15:38:28+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-2-download-and-start-eclipse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Download and Start Eclipse IDE</h2>

<p>Download Eclipse for Java Developers, extract and save it in any drive. It is totally free. You can run ‘eclipse.exe’ directly so you do not need to install Eclipse in your system.</p>

<p>&mdash; Tải về Eclipse dành cho người lập trình Java, giải nén và lưu nó ở bất cứ ổ đĩa nào.Eclipse là bộ công cụ phát triển code Java hoàn toàn miễn phí. Bạn có thể chạy trực tiếp file &ldquo;eclipse.exe&rdquo; nên không cần thiết bạn cài nó vào máy tính của bạn.</p>

<p>1) Go to <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads.">|Eclipse download page</a></p>

<p>&mdash; Ấn vào <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads.">đây</a> để vào trang website tải về Eclipse.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-1.png"></p>

<p>2) For Windows users, you will have to know what type of version of your OS you have. If your computer is a 64 bit Windows , select Windows 64 and if you have a 32 bit Windows, select Windows 32 bit.</p>

<p>&mdash; Đối với những người dùng hệ điều hành Window , bạn phải hiểu rõ WIN bạn đang chạy là 64 bit hay 32 bit để mà chọn Eclipse phù hợp.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-2.png"></p>

<p>3) Save the .zip file to your disk.</p>

<p>&mdash; Lưu tập tin vào ổ đĩa của bạn.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-3.png"></p>

<p>4) Once you have downloaded the Eclipse archive you will need to Extract the zip file, which will create the unzipped Eclipse folder.</p>

<p>&mdash; Khi tải về hoàn thành bạn sẽ có 1 file tên là eclipse.zip , bạn cần phải giải nén File này ra bằng winzar hay bằng 7-zip.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-4.png"></p>

<p>5) You may want to Extract the archive to the root of C: drive, thus creating the folder “C:eclipse”, or just moved the extracted eclipse folder to the root of C: drive if you extracted it already. I prefer to leave it as it is.</p>

<p>&mdash; Nó sẽ hỏi bạn là giải nén file này vào đâu.Bạn có thể chọn tất cả các ổ đĩa nhưng để dễ nhớ nên chọn vào ổ đĩa C.sau khi giải nén xong nó sẽ có 1 folder tên là eclipse.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-5.png"></p>

<p>6) Let the extraction process finished.</p>

<p>&mdash; Chờ cho việc giải nén hoàn thành.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-6.png"></p>

<p>7) Open the eclipse folder.</p>

<p>&mdash; Tìm vào đường dẫn lúc nãy bạn chọn để giải nén file, sẽ tìm thấy folder eclipse và click chuột vào folder đấy.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-7.png"></p>

<p>8) Since Eclipse IDE does not have any installer, there will be a file inside the Eclipse folder named eclipse.exe. You can double click on the file to run Eclipse.</p>

<p>Note:(This step is not required, but it’s strongly recommended.) Right-click the Eclipse Icon and press “Send To” &ndash;> “Desktop (Create Shortcut).” Now you will be able to launch Eclipse from your desktop.</p>

<p>&mdash; Sẽ có một file tên là eclipse.exe. Bạn nên tạo 1 shortcut cho file đấy và để nó ở màn hình desktop.Sau đó bạn ấn vào cái shortcut đấy nó sẽ mở eclipse lên cho bạn</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-8.png"></p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-9.png"></p>

<p>9) Create a workspace folder where you will contain all the program files you create.  You can choose whatever place you want for your workspace, but it’s easiest to just use the default you’re given. I like to choose my own workplace location and will place all my Toolsqa tutorial projects under it.</p>

<p>&mdash; Eclipse khi mở lần đầu sẽ yêu cầu bạn khởi tạo 1 nơi để nó lưu tất cả các project của bạn.Bạn cứ chọn cái mà nó đưa ra cho bạn chọn thôi.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Start-Eclipse-2.png"></p>

<p>10) You may see the window like this, this is the Welcome window for Eclipse.</p>

<p>&mdash; Bạn sẽ nhìn thấy 1 màn hình như hình dưới , nó là màn hình chào mừng của Eclipse.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-11.png"></p>

<p>11) Now that you have finished installing eclipse restart your computer. By restarting your computer it refreshes system memory and allows changes made by installers and uninstallers to take effect.</p>

<p>&mdash; Sau khi hoàn tất tôi khuyên bạn nên khởi động lại máy tính cho để máy tính giải thoát những bộ nhớ đệm không cần thiết được tạo ra bởi việc cài đặt.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newbie Part 1 :Download and Install Java]]></title>
    <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-1-download-and-install-java/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T15:36:12+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-1-download-and-install-java</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Download and Install Java (Tải và Cài Java)</h2>

<p>First of all you need to install JDK (Java development kit) in your system. So your next question will be “how can I download java”. <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html">Click here</a> to download Java and install it in your system as per given installation guide over there or follow the below mentioned steps.</p>

<p>&mdash; Điều đầu tiên bạn cần phải cài đặt JDK trong máy tính của bạn.Bạn có thể tải về bằng cách <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html">ấn vào đây</a> và làm theo hướng dẫn của trang website đó.Hoặc bạn có thể làm theo các bước mà tôi đã minh họa ở dưới.</p>

<p>1) Visit the <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html">Java downloads page</a> on Oracle’s website to find the JDK environment download. Scroll down until you find Java SE Latest Version and download JDK.</p>

<p>&mdash; Mở trang web cho phép download <a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html">Java</a> ở trên website Oracle.Kéo chuột tới đến khi nào bạn tìm thấy bản JAVA SE mới nhất và chọn tải về bộ cài JDK.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-1.png"></p>

<p>2) Once you have selected download, accept the terms of service and choose the correct OS corresponding for the specific JDK. (Windows, Mac, Linux, etc.)</p>

<p>&mdash; Khi ấn vào nút download , bạn phải chấp nhận điều khoản dịch vụ của JAVA (cái này thì không phải lo lắng gì đâu,cứ click vào thôi) và chọn đúng Java phù hợp với hệ điều hành máy tính của bạn.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-2.png"></p>

<p>3) Save the .exe file to your disk.</p>

<p>&mdash; Chọn nơi để bạn tải về file có đuôi exe</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-3.png"></p>

<p>4) Once the download is complete, double click the file to begin the installation of JDK.</p>

<p>&mdash; Khi tải về thành công , nhấp chuột 2 lần vào file mà bạn vừa tải về để bắt đầu cài JDK.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-4.png"></p>

<p>5) To run the installer, click Run.</p>

<p>&mdash; Để chạy bạn phải nhấn nút RUN</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-5.png"></p>

<p>6) The installation process starts. Click the Next button to continue the installation.</p>

<p>&mdash; Quá trình cài đặt bắt đầu. Nhấn nút Next để tiếp tục cài.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-6.png"></p>

<p>7) On the next screen you will encounter some options. Just leave these alone and click Next unless you know what you are doing.</p>

<p>&mdash; Bạn sẽ gặp phải những lựa chọn ở một số màn hình nhưng đừng quan tâm đến nó, cứ ấn nút Next.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-7.png"></p>

<p>8) After the initial installation is done, a pop up asking you where your source java files will be. You can choose to change where you want to keep your folder but it’s best to stick with what you were given first. Click Next to continue.</p>

<p>&mdash; Sẽ có 1 cửa sổ hiện ra để cho bạn chọn nơi lưu trữ JAVA. Bạn cứ ấn nút NEXT không phải quan tâm.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-8.png"></p>

<p>9) Let the installation finish.</p>

<p>&mdash; Chờ việc cài đặt hoàn thành.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-9.png"></p>

<p>10) A few brief dialogs confirm the last steps of the installation process; click Close on the last dialog. This will complete Java installation process.</p>

<p>&mdash; Hoàn tất việc cài đặt , bạn ấn nút CLOSE nhé.</p>

<p><img src="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/images/Download-And-Install-Java-10.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
