<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: NewBie | Selenium Tutorial]]></title>
  <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/categories/newbie/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-07T06:00:16+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ta Bao Lan]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[tabaolan1987@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginner with Selenium Ide Part 2: Record User Action and Export this Script to another langugae]]></title>
    <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/06/02/beginner-with-selenium-ide-part-2-record-user-action-and-export-this-script-to-another-langugae/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-02T15:03:46+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/06/02/beginner-with-selenium-ide-part-2-record-user-action-and-export-this-script-to-another-langugae</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>In this tutorial  , we will let you know how to record the user action in browser via Selenium IDE and How to export this to another language like java , &hellip;!</p>

<h3>Record User Action</h3>

<!--more-->


<p>1) Open Firefox Browser and click in the icon of Selenium IDE.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ide-3.png"></p>

<p>2) The GUI of Selenium Ide will show , click in the red circle button of the top to record user action.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ide-5.png"></p>

<p>3) Go back to the firefox driver and type to the url &ldquo;<a href="https://facebook.com">https://facebook.com</a>&rdquo;</p>

<p>4) Login to facebook as normal.</p>

<p>5) Back to Selenium IDE GUI , you will see it recorded your action.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ide-6.png"></p>

<p>6) Click in the button play to let Selenium IDE run again each action that you made before.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ide-7.png"></p>

<p>7) Now if you can save this test case as html file and re-run it by Open Selenium IDE and Open File &ndash;> choose the path you save this file.</p>

<h3>Export this test script to another language script.</h3>

<p>The most useful option is &ldquo;Export&rdquo; because it allows you to turn your Selenium IDE test cases into file formats that can run on Selenium Remote Control and WebDriver</p>

<p>Selenium IDE , test cases can be exported only to the following formats:</p>

<p>.cs (C# source code)</p>

<p>.java (Java source code)</p>

<p>.py (Python source code)</p>

<p>.rb (Ruby source code)</p>

<p>You just need click in menu File &ndash;> Export Test Case As.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ide-9.png"></p>

<p>Note : You need to know that some function when you export from Selenium IDE to another language will be fail. I suggest you need to re-check the export File by running it again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginner with Selenium Ide Part 1 : Download Selenium Ide and install in FireFox Browser]]></title>
    <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/06/02/beginner-with-selenium-ide-part-1-download-selenium-ide-and-install-in-firefox-browser/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-02T14:34:19+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/06/02/beginner-with-selenium-ide-part-1-download-selenium-ide-and-install-in-firefox-browser</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>Selenium IDE is a Firefox plugin which records and plays back user interactions with the browser. Use this to either create simple scripts or assist in exploratory testing. It can also export Remote Control or WebDriver scripts, though they tend to be somewhat brittle and should be overhauled into some sort of Page Object-y structure for any kind of resiliency.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>How to download and install to firefox browser</h3>

<p>1) Install Firefox browser and setup it to your computer by click into this <a href="http://adf.ly/p8vFO">link</a></p>

<p>2) Go to Selenium and download Selenium IDE by click into this <a href="http://adf.ly/p8uzn">link</a></p>

<p>3) Click to the version current of Selenium IDE</p>

<p><img src="/images/ide-1.png"></p>

<p>4) Click to &lsquo;Allow&rsquo; button if it existed in the top of browser.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ide-2.png"></p>

<p>5) Click on button &lsquo;Install Now&rsquo; when it enable.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ide-3.png"></p>

<p>6) After install please click in the &lsquo;Restart Now&rsquo; button in the top of browser</p>

<p>7) After restart you will see the icon of Selenium IDE show in the top of browser.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ide-3.png"></p>

<p>8) Now let us share with you how to playing with ide in the <a href="">Selenium IDE : User action record</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginner with Webdriver Part 4 : Configuration Eclipse with Selenium driver and Create Fisrt Test]]></title>
    <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/23/newbie-part-4-configuration-eclipse-with-selenium-driver-and-create-fisrt-test/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-23T15:13:27+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/23/newbie-part-4-configuration-eclipse-with-selenium-driver-and-create-fisrt-test</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Creat a simple test case selenium in Eclipse</h2>

<p>To configure Eclipse with Selenium webdriver, we need to launch the Eclipse IDE, create a Workspace, create a Project, create a Package, create a Class and add External libraries to the project.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>1) Select WorkSpace on Eclipse start up.</h3>

<p>a) Double click on ‘eclipse.exe’ to start eclipse. First time when you start eclipse, it will ask you to select your workspace where your work will be stored as shown in below image.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Start-Eclipse-1.png"></p>

<p>b) Create a “working directory” for all of your projects. Think of it like “My Documents” in the Windows operating system. It’s a folder which contains a lot of your documents, but there’s nothing to prevent you from creating another folder called “My Other Documents” (for instance) to house other documents.</p>

<p>Typically you only need one workspace, and you can think of it as your “My Documents” for Java code. If you wanted to, you could have more than one, but chances are you won’t have a use for more. I like to choose my own workplace location and will place all my ToolsQA tutorial projects under it.</p>

<p>You can change it later on from ‘Switch Workspace‘ under ‘File‘ menu of eclipse. After selecting workspace folder, Eclipse will be open.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Start-Eclipse-21.png"></p>

<p><img src="/images/Start-Eclipse-3.png"></p>

<p>c) You may see the window like this, this is the Welcome window for Eclipse. You may close this window.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Start-Eclipse-4.png"></p>

<h3>2) Create a new Project</h3>

<p>Projects: A collection of related code. Generally speaking, each project encompasses one independent program. Each programming assignment you do will typically require its own project.</p>

<p>Once you’ve established your workspace, you’ll want to create a project and begin writing code. In Eclipse, projects are the next-smallest functional unit after workspaces, but where you might have only one workspace, you will usually have several projects inside one workspace.</p>

<p>a) Create new Java Project from File > New > Project .</p>

<p><img src="/images/Setup-Project-1.png"></p>

<p>b) Select Java Project and click Next.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Setup-Project-2.png"></p>

<p>c) Give your Project name ‘OnlineStore‘ as shown in below given figures. Click on Finish button.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Setup-Project-3.png"></p>

<p>d) You may or may not see this message but if in case you get any, check Remember my decision and  click on Yes.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Setup-Project-4.png"></p>

<h3>3) Create a new Package</h3>

<p>a) Right click on Project name ‘OnlineStore‘ and select New > Package.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Creating-Package-1.png"></p>

<p>b) Give your Package name ‘automationFramework‘ and click on Finish button.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Creating-Package-2.png"></p>

<h3>4) Create a new Class</h3>

<p>Now that you have a project set up, you’re going to want start writing some new classes.</p>

<p>a) Right click on Package ‘automationFramework‘ and select New > Class.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Creating-Class-1.png"></p>

<p>b)  Give your Class name ‘FirstTestCase‘, check the option ‘public static void main‘ and click on Finish button. This will bring up totally a sweet class creation window.</p>

<p>Note: In case of not creating class for Main test case, please do not click ‘public static void main’. We need to select it only in case of writing test cases which we are going to execute and from where we call other classes. For functional classes, POM classes or any other classes we dont need this to be checked.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Creating-Class-2.png"></p>

<p>c) Now your Eclipse window will looks like bellow.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Creating-Class-3.png"></p>

<h3>5) Add External Jars to Java build path</h3>

<p>Now you need to add selenium webdriver’s jar files in to Java build path.</p>

<p>a) Right click on Project ‘OnlineStore‘ > Select Properties > Java build path. Then navigate to Libraries tab and click Add External JARs.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Selenium-Jar-1.png"></p>

<p>b) Add Selenium Java jar, you may add the source file too.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Selenium-Jar-2.png"></p>

<p>c) Add all the jars from the libs folder as well.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Selenium-Jar-3.png"></p>

<p>d) Click OK.</p>

<p>&mdash; Ấn nút Ok.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Selenium-Jar-4.png"></p>

<p>That’s all about configuration of WebDriver with eclipse. Now you are ready to write your test script in eclipse and run it in WebDriver.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Selenium-Jar-5.png"></p>

<h3>6) Write your First Test Case</h3>

<p>a) Copy &amp; paste the below code to your First Test Case class and give it a run.</p>

<p>```
package automationFramework;
import java.util.concurrent.TimeUnit;</p>

<p>import org.openqa.selenium.*;
import org.openqa.selenium.firefox.FirefoxDriver;</p>

<p>public class FirstTestCase {</p>

<pre><code>private static WebDriver driver = null;

public static void main(String[] args) {
    // Create a new instance of the Firefox driver
    driver = new FirefoxDriver();

    //Put a Implicit wait, this means that any search for elements on the page could take the time the implicit wait is set for before throwing exception
    driver.manage().timeouts().implicitlyWait(10, TimeUnit.SECONDS);

    //Launch the facebook
    driver.get("https://www.facebook.com/");


    // Find the element that's ID attribute is 'email' (Username)
    // Enter email on the element found by above desc.
    driver.findElement(By.id("email")).sendKeys('enter your username login to facebook')

    // Find the element that's ID attribute is 'pass' (Password)
    // Enter Password on the element found by the above desc.
     driver.findElement(By.id("pass")).sendKeys("enter your password login to facebook"); 

    // Now submit the form. WebDriver will find the form for us from the element 
    driver.findElement(By.Xpath("//form[@id='login_form']/table/tbody/tr[2]/td[3]/label/input")).click();

    // Print a Log In message to the screen
    System.out.println(" Login Successfully, now it is the time to Log Off buddy.");

    // Close the driver
    driver.quit();
        }
}
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>2) Now, to start the test just select Run > Run As > Java Application Or Right Click on Eclipse code and Click Run As  > Java Application</p>

<p>3) After a few Seconds a Mozilla browser will open  and you will see that with the help of your script, Selenium will Launch the Online Store, perform Sign in, display the Message, perform Log out and then Close the browser.</p>

<p>Once the execution is finished, you will see the message in Console section of the Eclipse IDE.</p>

<p>Now you will need to know about WebDriver in Selenium. I just create some basic knowledge about Webdriver please click <a href="/blog/categories/webdriver/">here</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginner with Webdriver Part 3 : Download Webdriver Java client]]></title>
    <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-3-download-webdriver-java-client/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T16:49:41+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-3-download-webdriver-java-client</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Download WebDriver Java client</h2>

<p>Selenium webdriver supports many languages and each language has its own client driver. Here we are configuring selenium 2 with Java so we need ‘webdriver Java client driver’.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>1) <a href="http://adf.ly/p8uzn">Click here</a> to go on WebDriver Java client driver download page for webdriver download file. On that page click on ‘Download‘ link of Java client driver as shown in the below image.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-1.png"></p>

<p>2) Save the zip file to your disk.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-2.png"></p>

<p>3) Once you have downloaded the archive you will need to Extract the zip file, which will create the unzipped Selenium Java folder.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-3.png"></p>

<p>4) You may want to Extract the archive to the folder where you are maintaing the test ware for your project. I like to extract it at the same location and then move it as per my needs.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-4.png"></p>

<p>5) Once the extraction process is complete, Open the Selenium folder.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-5.png"></p>

<p>6) There will be ‘libs’ folder, 2 jar files and change log in unzipped folder as shown in bellow figure. We will use all these files for configuring webdriver in eclipse.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-Webdriver-Java-Client-6.png"></p>

<p>7 ) Now you will take a look in the <a href="/blog/2014/05/23/newbie-part-4-configuration-eclipse-with-selenium-driver-and-create-fisrt-test/">Part 4 : Configuration Eclipse with Selenium driver and Create Fisrt Test</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginner with Webdriver Part 2 : Download and Start Eclipse]]></title>
    <link href="http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-2-download-and-start-eclipse/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-22T15:38:28+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tabaolan1987.github.io/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-2-download-and-start-eclipse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Download and Start Eclipse IDE</h2>

<p>Download Eclipse for Java Developers, extract and save it in any drive. It is totally free. You can run ‘eclipse.exe’ directly so you do not need to install Eclipse in your system.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>1) Go to <a href="http://adf.ly/p8uot">|Eclipse download page</a></p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-1.png"></p>

<p>2) For Windows users, you will have to know what type of version of your OS you have. If your computer is a 64 bit Windows , select Windows 64 and if you have a 32 bit Windows, select Windows 32 bit.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-2.png"></p>

<p>3) Save the .zip file to your disk.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-3.png"></p>

<p>4) Once you have downloaded the Eclipse archive you will need to Extract the zip file, which will create the unzipped Eclipse folder.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-4.png"></p>

<p>5) You may want to Extract the archive to the root of C: drive, thus creating the folder “C:eclipse”, or just moved the extracted eclipse folder to the root of C: drive if you extracted it already. I prefer to leave it as it is.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-5.png"></p>

<p>6) Let the extraction process finished.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-6.png"></p>

<p>7) Open the eclipse folder.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-7.png"></p>

<p>8) Since Eclipse IDE does not have any installer, there will be a file inside the Eclipse folder named eclipse.exe. You can double click on the file to run Eclipse.</p>

<p>Note:(This step is not required, but it’s strongly recommended.) Right-click the Eclipse Icon and press “Send To” &ndash;> “Desktop (Create Shortcut).” Now you will be able to launch Eclipse from your desktop.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-8.png"></p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-9.png"></p>

<p>9) Create a workspace folder where you will contain all the program files you create.  You can choose whatever place you want for your workspace, but it’s easiest to just use the default you’re given. I like to choose my own workplace location and will place all my Toolsqa tutorial projects under it.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Start-Eclipse-2.png"></p>

<p>10) You may see the window like this, this is the Welcome window for Eclipse.</p>

<p><img src="/images/Download-and-Install-Eclipse-11.png"></p>

<p>11) Now that you have finished installing eclipse restart your computer. By restarting your computer it refreshes system memory and allows changes made by installers and uninstallers to take effect.</p>

<p>12) Take a look in the next part <a href="/blog/2014/05/22/newbie-part-3-download-webdriver-java-client/">Part 3 : Download Webdriver Java client</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
